The V in viral stands for visual shock.
So if your video is not visual, it's not
going to go viral.
>> Today I'm talking to Jenny Hoyos, the
number one storyteller on social media.
She has built a YouTube empire with over
7 million subscribers and has billions
of views across all her channels. There
is no one that has mastered short form
storytelling like she has.
>> That curiosity gap, that is everything.
If an idea doesn't have a curiosity gap,
then there's no reason that the viewers
are going to watch.
>> In this video, we break down her formula
to make any idea go viral, the
storytelling structure behind most of
her unforgettable videos, and her number
one tip to become a magnetic
storyteller. Whether you're creator,
entrepreneur, or speaker, this one will
change how you tell stories forever.
>> So, I remember in one of the videos you
said that you could make any video or
any idea go viral. What makes a good
story for you?
>> A good story for short form content is
not one that is fast. Cuz I find a lot
of people start trying to stuff in a
bunch of information and just talk
really fast. Rather, a good story is one
that doesn't have many story beats and
has just the relevant ones to get to the
end of your story. Usually, you have a
goal in the you set out for a goal in
the beginning. you have a problem that
needs to get resolved and you only
include the very few story beats that
are relevant to answer that question.
>> And what entails a story beat? Is that
like a challenge and a resolution or
what does that entail?
>> Yeah, the the way I think about it
actually so I actually have a framework.
So it would be much easier if I just uh
say what those what those are. So uh
it's a new one I came up with like two
months ago and it has been working in
every video. So, super easy to remember.
It's the acronym viral. The V in viral
stands for visual shock.
>> So, if your video is not visual, it's
not going to go viral. It needs to be
visual. And it doesn't matter what niche
you're in. If you're in in an
entertainment niche, then I'm hoping
it's you're doing some sort of visual
challenge or some sort of uh visual
story. And if you're in an educational
niche, try to find a visual analogy,
whether that's like with marbles or if
you're using like for example the blue
ocean strategy. It's a marketing
strategy and it's very visual because
you think about a fisherman and there's
fish and there's a blue and red ocean.
Like it it visualizes it. So number one,
it needs to be visually engaging, but it
needs to start with a visual shock
element.
>> Um and then after that immediately start
the video. You want to start these short
form videos. Unlike movies where they
have to give us context and the why and
the motivation of the character, with
short form content, you have to get
right in to the juice, the peak action
like at the we're almost at the climax
already. That's where the video should
start.
>> Uh so immediately and immediately start
the video. So not giving context. And
then the R is rising action. We need
tension. So what's the question? What's
the problem? Tell us it. The A is
anticipation. You don't want to give the
answer immediately. You want to give us
little hints and clues and puzzle
pieces. And the L, a lasting payoff. You
want to make a concise ending that
concisely answers the question. And the
answer or if you're asking a question in
the beginning of the video, like what's
2 plus two? The last word you say in the
video needs to be four. If you say four
and make sure to people are going to
leave because they they heard four and
then they're going to leave. So, if
you're going to ask for some sort of
call to action, uh, part of that lasting
payoff is to say it before you give the
answer.
>> That's fascinating and so easy to
remember with viral. Can we go
>> so easy to remember? Yeah.
>> So easy. Can we go a little bit deeper
into some of those components and you
give our listeners some some of the tips
on how to master each one of the steps?
>> So, if we start off with for example the
first one visual.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And if we think of let's say someone
typical in the educational space, let's
say I'm a I'm a life coach and I some
want to make some videos about that. How
could I start for example with a an
enticing visual at the start?
>> Yeah. So there's either two ways of
doing it, which is like using an actual
study of something. So if it's like a a
research study and showing like um like
the the results or bar graph or if it's
not then giving some sort of analogy of
what it looks like. So for example, I've
seen um I I there's so many different
life coaches that have done this type or
psychologists that have done these
videos and I can't I wish I could find
it to show it, but usually they'll start
with like a bowl of of uh a specific
color. So, let's say it's like blue and
then they'll have a glass that has like
uh red water. So, there's blue water and
red water. And they'll usually say,
"Okay, this blue water is is you." And
this red water is someone giving you um
telling you something bad. Now, even if
they just say something small, your
water is still blue, but it's it's going
to um it's going to be turning a
different color. And no matter if you
add more blue water to it, it's going to
take a lot more blue water to turn it
from purple back to its original blue.
So like that's just like a an example.
Um I've seen another great example of a
this is one of the best videos I've ever
seen. This one I I definitely know the
the channel. So you could use this as an
example. Um Gohar Khan is the name of
the channel. He has a video where he has
a jar and he says, "Um,
so if we were to pour sand, rocks, and
golf balls into this jar, in what order
should we pour it in so we can fill it
completely up?" And then the video is
him saying, "Well, let's start with the
sand and putting the rocks." Oh, wait.
There's no space for the golf balls.
Okay, let's do the rocks, then the sand,
then the golf ball. There's still no
space. But if you put the golf balls
first, then the rocks, then the sand,
then there is space. And that's because
the way you should be allocating your
time is by doing the bigger tasks
because that's how you should start your
day. You should start it with that
foundation and then the little tasks
will have space to be filled up at the
end. That was such a great video um
analogy. So just try to always think of
visual analogies.
>> Got it. That's fascinating. Yeah.
Instead of just using the analogy word
for word, you really you paint the scene
by playing it out real life.
>> Yes.
>> And so the second one was immediate
action. I think that's clear just boom,
you start with the momentum. Can you
share a little bit more about the third
one of how can you get that was rising
um what was the third one?
>> Yeah, like rising action rising action.
We need we need to know
>> we need to know what we're watching for.
So I think this one is um this one well
they're actually all just important but
I think people struggle with R and A
which is like what is this conflict?
What is what is this um anticipation as
well? So I think we can combine those.
The way I think about it is we're
immediately so we have that visual
analogy we're immediately starting but
why are we watching until the end?
That's why I think about rising action
like what why are we okay not only is
what are we watching till the end for
but why should we care cuz the question
you you you in theory could do something
like how do I make my coffee okay but
there's no there's nothing like
>> making me intrigued about that yeah
that's a question that that you're going
to give me the answer to but but make us
make us care so is it because um this is
how I make the coffee that keeps me
awake for more than 24 hours. What?
That's insane. Okay, I need to know how
you make that coffee.
>> So, you increase the stakes. What are
your other preferred ways of how do you
make your audience care? That's I guess
one thing is time pressure. What are
some other ways where you feel like this
really um goes well with any audience?
Definitely I would say speaking to them
something I didn't mention on in this
whole framework because it all comes it
you know first comes the idea before we
we even get to this framework of course
um but making them care kind of does
come back to the idea and making sure
that it revolves around them. So
whatever like if you're doing something
in a video are you do you're doing that
to test it for the audience. Um or at
the end of it they're going to get some
sort of value. So you'll make them care
by tapping into what they care about.
Think about what makes them scared, what
is going to excite them. What are their
dreams? What are their um nightmares?
>> Got it. Yeah. So the video should
address something specifically that they
think ah I need to have to solve or this
is what I'm always fear fe feared about
>> 100%. And something I want to add to
that is it's the the wording like the
certain way you word things or the order
of the way you say things makes a huge
difference because you could say two of
the same sentences and they end up
having two different meanings just
because of the way that you rearranged
it. Uh for that reason, that's why you
always want to start your video by
starting with you and then going to me.
So like if if uh recently I saw a video
where someone said that they were
training um to run like a marathon,
right? Instead of starting the video by
saying I'm training to run a marathon,
you want to start by saying here's how
you you should train for your next
marathon because this is what I'm doing.
like just by like a rearranging the the
way you said it and and saying it
exactly like that isn't the most
optimized way but the point is we always
start with them and then talk about you.
>> That is so fascinating because a lot of
creators out there they just talk from
their own experience without including
their audience necessarily.
>> Oh no the best creators always talk
about their audience first. Even someone
like Dan Martell has such a great
formula and all, even in his long form
videos where, for example, if he has a
listical videos of like five tips, he
always says the tip first and tells them
how to apply it. So, it's usually like a
three-step thing where he's like um the
tip, how you apply it, and then his
background and his story um with that
specific experience. So, he's starting
with them.
>> Got it. Okay. Fascinating.
And so raising anticipation is making
them care.
Anything else that you feel this is what
someone definitely has to have in their
story in order for the story to land
really well.
>> Yeah. Uh, another thing that is very
difficult to do which will I I say is
like part of the anticipation stage is
making sure the viewer is understanding
how close like where we are in the
story, how close we are to finishing
because if they feel like there's no end
in sight, then they're just going to
leave cuz they're just going to get
bored. So, we want it we want it to feel
like we are constantly progressing.
Progression is super important. So,
making sure that you are using language
that makes it feel like we're
progressing, like first, second, or um
or even including mechanisms like what I
like to do is um I like to include like
if if the video is is me doing something
in a certain amount of time, I'll have
the timer on screen. If I'm doing a a
recipe, for example, I'll have the
ingredients on the top of the screen and
then I'll check mark as I'm going
through the ingredients so they
understand how close we are to the video
being completed.
>> M got it. That's a good trick one. I'll
try this one.
If you think you've by now probably
analyzed millions of videos.
If you think is are there maybe like
three mistakes that you see are the most
common one that is stopping people from
going viral where you feel like if they
just fix this one thing then it would
make such a big difference.
I I definitely think it's it's selfish
content and it's that people talk about
them and not about the value that the
person's going to get. Um but I think
that all stems from not understanding
their avatar or sometimes not even
having an avatar. So I think it is
really important to know who you are
creating content for and ensuring that
it is a market that has high demand and
low supply because you can be in a
market that has high demand um but
there's a high supply of content
creators creating that content. So you
now can't be like a B like level
creator. you need to be A++ the best at
that niche
>> versus if you're in a niche where uh the
competitors are like creating content at
a C level you being at a B means you're
already the best at than everyone there.
So um I would say knowing your avatar
but also ensuring that you pick an
avatar or a niche or you know those
those things are are similar. If you
pick an avatar then it it typically
falls under a niche. Um, I think it's
super important. I think that's I think
that's that's I've seen creators who
would try to I I've seen uh creators
who've tried to be entertainment
creators and they wouldn't get views
because they're competing against Mr.
Beast and then they niche down.
Actually, I literally have a a friend
that I I've helped. His name is Josh
Krueger. He was he was doing like okay
like in this uh in the entertainment
niche uh basically competing against
like Iraq, Ryan Tran, Mr. beast. But
then he niched down into scootering
content and now he is the best
scootering content creator. Like it's
it's crazy how just switching niches can
make someone instantly go viral.
>> That is fascinating. Yeah, that's so
good to know cuz yeah, if we keep in
mind oftenimes, especially when it comes
to educational content or also business
content right there the bar is
relatively low but if we take the uh
entertainment space it's pretty high. So
if you apply some learnings,
>> wow, fascinating.
>> You talked about idea before.
How can I come up with those viral
ideas?
>> Yeah, there's different ways to do it
and I guess it all comes down to like
what your niche is and you know based on
that you'll know which is the best
option. Like for example, for
entertainment content creators, I would
say that looking for outliers is the
best thing. So essentially going on
YouTube or platforms like view stats and
seeing videos that are performing higher
than average on the person's channel. So
I used to do this all all the time where
you would go and look for small content
creators like less than a thousand
subscribers and have gotten over a
100,000 views on a video.
>> That means their idea whatever they did
was good and you should recreate that.
So that's that's one way and I think
that primarily works for entertainment
content creators but as far as other
creators um I guess it also works for
for niches in a way but then even so the
issue with that is uh if the video has
just come out and you create your own
version how are you going to how are you
going to do better than them or I guess
you'd have to like find like with
entertainment content you can find a
twist but if it's like educational like
what twist are you going to do? I guess
you could try to make the video better,
but anyway, because of that, it's also
good to have your own unique ideas. And
uh my favorite way is actually just
through my own experiences
um or like through content that I am
consuming in other formats like uh books
or TV. Um but I really like trying to
acknowledge like everything that happens
in your real life because everything is
an idea. Um like literally like it's
actually insane how how um everything is
an idea for example
you know how you you let's say waking up
in the morning the first thing you do is
grab your phone that's a hook or do you
is the first thing you do in the morning
do you grab your phone or do you grab
your phone first thing in the morning
boom that's that's a hook um
everything's a hook even putting on your
shoes I saw a relatable video on how
like um instead of untying your shoes.
Does anyone else just like slip them on
and like actually spend longer trying to
put them on with the laces tied than
just untying them and tying them back
on? Like that's that's viral.
>> I think uh trying to acknowledge like
things that happen in your day-to-day is
really good because it happens to other
people too and it probably hasn't been
created yet.
When people think of storytelling, they
often think that it has to have this
challenge that you or this mission that
you stayed up front where like hey over
the next 3 days I'm going to cut out all
all the carbs in my life or I'm going to
not going to look at my phone. People
think that this is the way how they
create stories. Would you say that this
is how you usually look for ideas? It's
usually those challenges type of videos
or is there a better way? Those are my
favorite stories for sure cuz the reason
why I like those I like for for me
personally is because when I'm going
into it, I don't know what's going to
happen either. So if I don't know what's
going to happen, then the viewers
definitely don't know what's going to
happen. But you can definitely
incorporate storytelling tactics in
videos that don't have those traditional
challengebased stories. It's just a bit
trickier and you have to be more
specific in the way that you are writing
it. I would say
>> if we take those challenge type of
stories. One thing that I struggle with
myself is that oftentimes I want to do a
challenge but it seems like hey how do I
compress that then into a 60-second
video right let's say I go through this
three-day challenge where I'm let's say
I'm trying to speak more articulate and
I'm documenting this but then it feels
like hey how can I put this then in a
60-second video.
Yeah, that for that reason. Actually,
the first thing I'll say is I find that
the best short form challenges last 10
minutes, not even maybe an hour max
because you we don't want to have a lot
of story beats. And if you were to break
it up into three days, unfortunately,
we'd be break
because we don't want that many story
beats. We would probably just say on day
one, I felt three sentences. Day two, I
felt three sentences. Day three, I felt
three sentences. But you can't just
break up an entire day into three
sentences. Um, especially if it's a
challenge, like for example, if the
challenge is like eating a healthy diet,
imagine breaking up on day one, I eat
this for breakfast with this, this,
this, this, this, this, this, this,
this, this, this, this, and that, lunch,
like it's a lot.
>> So, for that reason, I would actually
encourage a a long form video. I
wouldn't even say a short form series. I
know people do short form series. um
those work on Instagram, maybe Tik Tok,
but for YouTube or just short form
content in general, I wouldn't do a
series. In that case, I would just make
a long form.
>> Got it.
>> But yeah, the best challenges, think of
challenges that like last uh like for
short form,
>> they really do need to be short stories.
You need to tell stories that are really
like actually just don't have much going
on.
>> Okay, that's good to know. And so if we
take for example some educational
creators out there, let's say we have
this agency owner or again we have this
life coach. What could be like a
10-minute challenge that they could
record or document?
>> I guess it depends. Like uh I've seen
videos where people make a short where
they try and close a client on a cold
call. Like that's that's a a challenge
they could do. or um
could you give me like a specific niche
that I could think about?
>> Yeah,
let's see. Let's let's stick with life
coaches then for a second. And so, hey,
you are in the niche, let's say, of
helping helping men with confidence.
>> Okay.
>> Very relatable.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I I love that. I am uh
almost wondering if there is some sort
of exercise that you can do for
self-confidence or maybe if there are
certain I guess like a
that actually reminds me of a video I
just I just saw of someone like talking
about like how before you do anything
that is is going to be publicly or you
need to be confident like just to like
shake and and and uh be crazy. Have you
heard about that tip?
>> Yeah.
>> How like you just want to like shake
everything off like get all the energy.
>> I do that all the time. Every single
time before podcast before I go on
stage, I shake out my body and I do warm
up routine.
>> Okay, there we go. That that's that's
like a a video or uh testing out. It
could be even actually
because it's not an episodic series. It
could be a non-epodic series where
you're testing out different um warm-up
routines. So, um
yeah, the video could start like that
trying and then blank celebrities uh
warm-up routine before um speaking and
then giving it a rating and then doing
different videos where you give it
different ratings and you don't have to
say that they're they're linked, but
that's a format that's a great format.
>> Um and it's visual because you're you're
you're shaking it all off. Um,
>> but
yeah, I would say challenges don't
always need to be like what is like
typically seen on YouTube where it's
like how long can I hold my breath or
something like that. It doesn't need to
always be like that. Um, a challenge is
ultimately a problem that you want to
resolve.
>> Yeah.
And it can be the smallest problem
possible as long as as it has a visual
hook at the start and some progression
throughout and a lot of twists in there.
And so
>> that they care about. Yeah.
>> That they care about. And so what I hear
from you is don't try to find the super
unique one big challenge because
oftentimes this might be a little bit
too much for those shorts but rather
more those short relatable things that
people ask themselves. Ah I was actually
curious about that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, shorts are are meant
to be short. It's like I feel like a
good example is um I I saw a long form
video where someone it was like an hour
long where someone like went through the
different fruits and the nutrition value
that you get from them and which and
then ranking like basically they did a
tier list of fruits and then they like
explained in thorough each fruit for an
hour.
A short would be um
literally just doing each individual
fruit. Um like the video would be
showing a tier list with with one fruit
of or one fruit of each kind on S
through F and then saying so they
already see which fruits are there. What
tier would we put an app? Oh my
goodness, this is a viral video. Okay.
What? And then showing the the tier list
and hooking with what tier would an
apple go on? Well, it has a lot of
fiber, but it also has a lot of sugar.
And then when you look at the amount of
fat in relative to this and that and
blah blah blah, and then you build it
up. So, so basically, you want to tell
the story where it's like, it has this,
but it's that. It has this, but it has
that. And ultimately, for that reason, I
give Apple a tier. And that's the end of
the video.
>> So, that's that's also like a a
question. I mean, yeah, it's it is kind
of like a it's a challenge. It's like a
game.
>> It's fun. That that's Oh my goodness. I
hope someone does that. I hope someone
does that. That's so good.
>> That would be so fun. Someone after
watching this video is going to do that.
>> Yeah. No, that that's good.
>> That's so cool.
Are there any other ways how I can come
up with those viral video ideas?
Honestly,
I primarily focus on natural experiences
and outliers and I just try to get as
many as I as I can through that. Um,
just writing down everything to be
honest. I mean, of course, the obvious
the obvious thing I haven't mentioned
yet is is AI, but I think the way that I
think about ideiation is there's no
specific tool that's going to give you
the idea. Even AI, AI is not going to
give you the idea. There's a bunch of
these different things that can give you
a tons of ideas. So, you could um you
can share with AI, have it brainstorm a
whole list. But what I what I recommend
is just gathering at least 100 ideas and
picking out one of those 100, the one
idea that people actually care about
that will be able to follow that
framework.
>> Jenny, can you walk us through your
process of using AI for ideiation?
Yeah. So, for one, I use a custom GPT
that I created by essentially uh putting
in like a 50-page SOP, which is a
standard operating procedure, which in
other words, uh for those for those
watching um or listening. So, whenever I
hire someone onto the team, I give them
a 50-page PDF.
It it sounds very long actually for them
where they read through my entire
process. I basically just like in detail
wrote down everything I do from
ideiation, scripting, um filming,
editing. Literally, no matter what
you're doing, you could be an editor and
you're going to learn about my ideation
process because you're also going to be
in the story and you're going to want to
know you're going to want to know the
context and even the ideator. I'm I hope
they understand what the editors are
going going through so that they know
that we don't want to be producing some
sort of crazy thing. We we don't want to
do it in post. We want have to do it
when filming. Anyway, so I have a
50-page thing that explains everything I
do and also more about my avatar, my
mission, vision, uh my goal, and so
that's in my my custom GPT. So, um my
students have the have that as have
access to that as well, which is pretty
cool. But from there um oh because the
GPT doesn't actually have my mission
vision um because I use the same one
that uh all my students use. So I have
the SOP I have the custom GPT then I
give it my avatar my mission I have a I
upload two PDFs. So I have another PDF
two pages actually very short just
explaining my channel and different and
similar channels. Um and then from there
I just ask it to give me viral ideas.
Um, and it'll give me viral ideas, but
ideally you're giving it some sort of of
like topic or some sort of format to
start with. So, for example, I like to
say, give me ideas um that start with
the hook, is it possible to blank or
what happens if blank? Because those are
the type of videos that I I like to do.
>> What happens if is it possible if to
>> Yeah, always questions. I always give it
like um those questions so it knows to
give me an idea that isn't a statement
because sometimes AI will just tell you
like picking an apple out of a tree and
it's like okay what what does that have
to do versus it's like is it possible to
grow an apple tree without a seed like
oh wait what now now it's like
interesting
>> okay so it has to has the this surprise
component in there
Yeah, that curiosity gap that is
everything. If an idea doesn't have a
curiosity gap, then there's no reason
that the viewers are going to watch.
>> There's there's no reason to watch.
>> If you had to give your viewers, your
listeners,
one or two tips to become a much more
captivating storyteller, what would it
be?
on on on specifically video content.
>> Yeah.
>> The way you speak is everything. I've
seen people like you can take the same
script and someone's if someone says it
without any enthusiasm or suspense, then
the viewer isn't going to be engaged.
Don't sound robotic. I think that is
like the biggest thing. The the way you
say something really makes a difference.
You could be saying nothing. you could
be saying nothing, but if you're talking
like something's about to happen, people
are instantly gonna be hooked.
>> Uh, so so I would say that's that's a
huge tip that is underlooked. Um, but
another thing I would say is also
similar to that
is not having the same pacing
throughout. So typically for my videos,
I always have like the first 15 seconds
is like lots of things are happening,
things are moving quickly and then
things kind of slow down to a medium
pace from that 15 to 30 second range.
Then from 30 seconds forward, everything
is like super like slow, but not like
slow in a way where it's like we're not
progressing. Slow like wait, something
like the suspense is about to happen.
So, the way I think about it is like um
actually I have this video where I
tested if you can break an unbreakable
glass and like the beginning of the
video was like method one, method two,
method three, method four, and then um
method five and then it slows down. It's
like, okay, I'm kind of nervous. I think
this is going to work, guys. And then
and then I I throw it off a building and
then we let that play out actually in
slow motion. It's falling off the
building in slow motion. And then before
it falls, we cut back to me. Okay, I'm
gonna go check out the cup to see it
right now. And then we reveal like
because that's when people are most
engaged. People are invested because of
the suspense.
>> That is so powerful. Yeah. Slowing down
before the big reveal. So boom, boom,
boom, boom. And then
>> Yeah.
>> Beautiful. I love this.
>> That is That is so cool. I love this.
Now, I've seen that you've been also
fairly active when it comes to long form
storytelling, but I think you stopped
posting there, right?
>> Temporarily. I mean, I'm working on a
couple of them.
>> Okay. So, what would you say is the
biggest difference long form
storytelling versus short form
storytelling?
>> Oh, for sure. It's definitely that
they're just bigger stories that have
more story beats. Um and that is usually
because there is more days or there are
more elements to it. So um going back to
like the fruit example, it's like one
fruit versus all the fruits. That's how
I think about long form. I think about
long form in the way that if you were to
clip out a bunch of sections, it can
work as a short. I mean, look at like
Mr. Even like, and it's not even just
the way I execute it. Mr. Beast does
this himself. And one of his most
popular formats is um $1 versus $1
million vacation or $1 versus $1 million
date, $1 versus $1 million job. He has
like a bunch of formats where he does
that. Uh hotel, planes, etc.
That is a long form where he's testing
out all those different things. He could
easily make a short and he has where he
just reviews a $1 hotel, a $10 hotel,
and that in itself is an entire short.
So, I think about a long form and
especially if you're a short form
creator moving into long form, think
about long form as a bunch of sort
shorts back toback that fall under the
same theme. Even if you look at like I
love Dan Martell's videos, his are
usually like 10 tips of something. If
you were to clip them out, they're all
shorts. Think of a bunch of shorts ideas
that fall under one umbrella, one theme,
and then make that into a long form.
>> I love this.
>> And it like answers one big story.
>> Uhhuh. Yeah. And so almost every minute
should be a standalone video by itself
that it has its own viral characters as
well.
>> Exactly. Yep.
>> Got it. Okay. This is so cool.
>> Do you see any other big differences
long form versus short form or do you
feel that those are the things that you
change the most in order to be
successful on long form?
I would say that is the main thing.
However, of course, long form has a
title and thumbnail versus short form.
Well, they do, but they don't. So, on
long form, someone needs to click on
your video to watch it. On short form,
someone has already ran into your video
and you just have to keep them hooked.
So, the way that you hook on long form
versus short form is very different. The
way I think about a short form hook is
the way you should think about a long
form title and thumbnail. So when I
think about hooking with the t with
hooking in long form. So if if the title
thumbnail is a hook, then what is the
actual hook? So basically the title
thumbnail should be very similar to a
short where it's it's visual. There's a
curiosity gap. There's a reason to care.
You have the reason to care within
there. Um so when someone clicks on it,
you want to now prove the title and
thumbnail. That's that's the difference.
You don't want to restate what you just
said, rather you want to prove that in
this video we're going to be doing what
we just talked about and then also give
more. So, not only did they click, but
now they're getting more on top of it.
So, the way I think about it is
typically there should be like a
multiple reasons to care in your video.
Even with shorts, but mainly in long
form, they shouldn't only just be
watching for that a plot. the A plot
being what they what they clicked on.
They should also be watching for that
that B reason. I think Ryan Dan's one of
the best creators at this. Right now,
he's doing his 50 states in 50 days
series.
>> The Aplot is he's visiting 50 Airbnbs in
50 days. But the Bplot is he's doing it
to raise money for charity. And that's
why people are going to keep tun tuning
in. Yeah, it's cool. I want to see this
really cool Airbnb in this random state.
That's why I'm in. But now I'm invested
in him this entire series because I want
to see if he's able to raise a million
dollars.
>> Mhm. So it's the question below the main
quest.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Fascinating.
>> It gets really complex because um in
short form there
the best short form videos have a Bplot
but it is very hard to incorporate a
Bplot or to incorporate a complex Bplot.
So when I do it, it's usually very
simplistic, but with long form, I would
say a Bplot is is uh is is pretty
essential if you're going to keep people
invested for a long time.
>> Mhm.
I remember the thing that held me back
the most and going into long form
storytelling was that the whole filming
process just seemed so so so much work
like to have constantly camera from
every single angle on you. Yeah.
>> What would be what would be your tip to
get a little bit over this overwhelm
where it just feels like it's so much
work? Like how do you do with that?
>> 100%. It it is a lot of work. And
something I I always tell people is to
have that that one place where you
always film and have the thing set up
there and it's like you know exactly how
it is. It's the first time it's going to
be difficult, but it's going to be
familiar each time and I think that
makes it very easy. Um, so I film a lot
of videos in my kitchen and now it's
like muscle memory where where the
tripod goes, where the light goes and
and how everything is and it's like
setting it up is is quick and easy. And
something I want to say because I
already know what people are thinking um
or some people because I've told this to
people and I usually like the number one
piece of feedback I get whenever I say
that is oh but people are going to be
bored of seeing this the same thing like
don't they want to see different places
like my channel is going to 50 different
Airbnbs. Um, and the answer I tell them
is no. People like familiarity.
>> Look at the best shows. Look at friends.
Every single episode was them in the
coffee shop and the camera's is in the
same angle every time. Or not even just
them. You look at every single TV show
or any like family show. The the camera
is really everything is in the same
place every single time. Do you notice
that as well?
>> And it's it's familiarity
[Music]
>> that is so relieving to everyone, right?
that needs things fancy gear. I need to
go outside. I need to do this. Just
Yeah. Stay in the same setup once you
have found the setup that you like.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> That's why a lot of people have studios
and I think or a lot of creators as they
get bigger, they end up getting studios
because it's very convenient. Like for
me, I can't leave a tripod in the
kitchen. But once you get a studio, um
because I've seen creators like have a
studio with the kitchen and you can just
leave everything there and all you have
to do is turn it on.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That seems to be making
things much easier.
Jenny, if you were to give a tip to
someone that is just starting out right
now, short form storytelling, and he's
like, I want to be like Jenny, what
would be the tip that you would give to
that person?
>> The number one tip to
go viral on shorts, I guess. Mhm.
>> The number one tip
because I feel like I've mentioned all
of them. I want to go back to
the the high demand, low supply, because
that that is everything. Your video
could suck, but if no one has made that
video idea and people are trying to to
learn what it is that you're you're
talking about, then you're going to get
views. And it's very hard to find that.
But once you do,
you're going to get a bunch of viewers
on that video, and you just want to
create similar videos for that audience.
And um over time, you build a baseline
level of viewership.
I love this. This reminds me a little
bit of business. In business, often
times people go through an entire
industry and look for what are the
companies out there and where is maybe a
niche that is not being served too well.
And the same analytical mindset you can
apply then to YouTube and you just
analyze niche by niche and think hey
what is the competition out there how
much views are coming in and what could
be the unique edge there.
>> Yep. Exactly. Um so think about
something that you love or a tip that
I've heard creators say. This is how I I
figured out my niche when I first
started was um cuz I when I was first
getting started, I heard that this was
like a good idea and I heard creators I
heard one creator ask their I heard a
creator ask their friend like, "I don't
know what niche should do. Like what
should I do?" And I heard the creator
tell that other one. They said, "Well,
if you weren't creating content, what
would you do?" Like what what would you
want to do for work?
>> Like what would you want your your job
to be? Or like dream job that is not
like what are you currently doing? Um,
and then you want to create a content
around that that niche. I mean, like
Michael Reeves uh is a great channel. He
does like engine engineering content
creation or he does like he engineers
like these really cool things. He
doesn't even have like an engineering
degree or like learn computer like he
learned computer science completely by
him by himself, but the things he's
building are insane. Um, and that's why
when I started my channel, I actually
started with finance because I of course
wanted to do content creation, but um,
if it didn't work, I was always just
going to be like an investment banker.
That's what I was going to get into. So,
it's like, oh, naturally, you might as
well just make content around around
that then. Um, but even so, like
recently, I do a lot of cooking content
because now like I think to myself like
if because the answer is different now.
Now, if if I wasn't a creator, what
would I want to do? Like, I would want
to have my own restaurant. Like, that
would be fun to be cooking. And it's
like, oh, just create content around
that cuz that's what you have the most
fun with. And the reason why I say that
is to find a niche and something that
you love is because when you love
something, you're going to keep doing it
even if it's not working.
>> If you love something so much, you're
going to keep doing it even Sorry. If
you love something so much, then you're
going to keep doing it no matter what.
even if it's not working is what I'm
trying to say. Um
yeah. Yeah. I mean that's why I tried so
many side hustles um back then when I
wanted to like I wanted I wanted to be
this entrepreneur and start a bunch of
businesses. Um and I would always do all
these different things. I would try
dropshipping. I tried like uh coding. I
tried creating websites. I tried doing
all these different things. But none of
it worked because I would always quit
one to two weeks in. But YouTube worked
because I did it for over a year without
it even working.
>> Wow. Yeah, that's persistence.
How do you feel about not being an
investment banker?
>> Oh, I'm so glad. I'm so glad. I don't
even know why I studied like Well, I
guess finance is a good uh thing to
study, but it's funny because I'm not
even passionate about it anymore. Now
it's like I just love content creation.
>> Yeah.
That would be so funny to imagine you
right now in some office.
>> Yeah. But I guess it I guess it worked
out though because it's it's very
important with this this type of career
to know how to manage your money and uh
be responsible with your investments.
>> True. And last question, what's next for
you? What let's say where do you want to
what is your big goal in the future?
>> I have a lot of goals. So,
I want to have my company be worth $100
million,
but I also want to do that in a way that
I am enjoying and I'm enjoying the
process, having fun, and I'm also
happy with the way I did it because I
can easily sell out and do a bunch of
sponsorships that I don't want to do.
Like I mean I could do a uh you know
those gambling websites like oh those
people get paid so much whenever they
promote that. I I could do that if I
wanted to. I'm not going to do that. So
I I want to get my company worth um $100
million and I want to do it through a
way where I am actually helping people
because at the end of the day you get
paid like any person the reason that
every single person gets paid is because
they are providing some sort of value.
If you're not providing value, then you
are not going to make money unless
you're just robbing. Like you like it
doesn't matter who you are, you get paid
because you're providing some sort of
value or service. So, um yeah, and the
biggest thing that I'm genuinely
passionate about and I'm trying to work
into my content is just healthier living
in every facet. So healthier like eating
healthier or getting active is directly
but also healthier living in the sense
of being nice to your community,
spending time with your friends and
family. Uh being conscious about your
money and and making sure that you are
um saving it and not wasting it. So that
is something I want to I want to do. I
want to encourage kids to have a a good
healthy lifestyle.
>> Beautiful. Jenny, just one follow-up
question. this. Why 100 million?
>> Yeah. Um, that's a good question. I
guess it's not because I need $100
million. Um, I don't even like I don't
even buy anything. Like I don't even
have the desire to have anything like
that. I just want to know that like I
can do it. Like it's it's uh it's a huge
accomplishment. Um, but I know money
isn't isn't isn't everything. I just
want to know that I'm able to like my
business skills are able to do something
uh able to get there.
>> Beautiful. Jenny, thank you so much. It
has been absolute privilege having you
here and yeah, super excited to see the
progress over the next few months,
years. And anyone who hasn't checked out
Jenny's content yet, it's absolutely
crazy. She's really the master when it
comes to storytelling. Um, Jenny, is
there anything else that you would like
to share that how people can find you,
what they should check out?
>> Yeah. So, if you want to check out my
content, I'm on YouTube, jenny hoyos.
And if you have any questions or want to
work together, just email
teamjennyhoyos.com.
I'll be responding directly. Typically,
what I encourage people is to let me
know about where you're currently at in
your journey and where you're trying to
get because I offer a bunch of different
services or sometimes if you just have a
small question, I'll just go ahead and
answer it. Um, so let me know like what
you what you guys need or are struggling
with and I'm happy to help.
>> Wonderful. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah, thank you for having me.